Lillian Covillo Papers D022
University of Denver Libraries, Special Collections and Archives
Lillian Covillo Papers
1936-2010
University of Denver Libraries, Special Collections and Archives
Covillo, Lillian, 1921-
D022
3 Linear Feet (1 letter document box, 2 flat bes)
General
There is no accession record for these materials.
Covillo, Lillian, 1921-
- Work with Denver Grand Opera, 1936-1945; D022.01; 5 Items (5 file folders) file folder
  Arrangement
  Series 1 is arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  Series 1 of 8 is a compilation of materials that cover Lillian Covillo's early work with the Denver Grand Opera Company.
  Dance; Ballet; Colorado; Dancers; Ballerinas; Ballet dancers; Covillo, Lillian, 1921-; Covillo, Lillian, 1921-
- Lillian’s Own Dance Work, 1940-1955; D022.02; 6 Items (6 file folders) file folder
  Series 2 is arranged chronologically. __Lillian Covillo's work with the Martha Wilcox Dance Group is separated from her dance studios work. Oversized items are in oversized photo box
  Separated Materials
  Lillian Covillo's work with the Martha Wilcox Dance Group is separated from her dance studios work. Oversized items are in oversized photo box
  Series 2 of 8 documents Lillian Covillo's work as dancer, teacher, and studio owner before the Colorado Ballet. It includes photos and programs.
  Covillo, Lillian, 1921-
- Freidann Parker, circa 1940-circa 1950; D022.03; 6 Items file folder
  Series 3 is arranged as close to chronologically as possible. __Oversized items are in oversized photo box
  Oversized items are in oversized photo box
  Series 3 of 8 covers material related to Freidann Parker outside of her work with Lillian Covillo. It includes photos and one program.
- Students' Dancing, circa 1944; D022.04; 3 Items file folder
  Series 4 items are arranged by performance and student as best as possible __Oversized items are in oversized photo box.
  Oversized items are in oversized photo box.
  Series 4 of 8 covers photos of students from Lillian Covillo's various schools of dance.
- Ephemera, circa 1940-2010; D022.05; 3 Items file folder
  Series 5 is arranged chronologically __Oversized items are in oversized photo box
  Series 5 of 8 covers programs, pamphlets, and clippings that relate to Lillian Covillo as a child, a much older adult, and a ballet enthusiast around the world. It includes her funeral program and programs from other ballet companies she may have enjoyed.
- Newspaper Clippings, circa 1940-circa 1975; D022.06; 7 Items file folder
  Series 6 items, for the most part, lack dates so like items are grouped in folders and folders are arranged arbitrarily.
  Series 6 of 8 contains newspaper clippings about the Lillian Covillo's personal life, her dance work, her student's lives, and those of her friends.
- Colorado Concert Ballet and Colorado Ballet, circa 1968-circa 2000; D022.07; 1 Items This series contains one file folder and one spiral bound scrapbook. It shares a flat box with Series 8 items flat box (15 x 19 x 3 inches)
  Series 7 items were organized in scrapbook before they became part of the collection. All other items are in a second folder
  Series 7 of 8 contains a late 60's scrapbook of company rehearsal and performance and newspaper clippings related to the company.
- Scrapbook, 1936-1944; D022.08; 1 Items This is one scrpbook that shares a flat box with Series 7 items flat box (15 x 19 x 3 inches)
  Series 8 was arranged before it became part of the collection but is mostly chonological.
  Series 8 of 8 is a scrapbook compiled by Lillian Covillo's mother, Mrs. John Covillo. It covers Lillian Covillo's early dance work with photos, programs, notes, and newspaper clippings.
- Box 1, D022.0001; 1 Items letter document box (Box D022.0001)
- Box 2, D022.0002; 1 Items flat box (13 x 10 x 3 inches) (Box D022.0002)
- Box 3, D022.0003; 1 Items flat box (13 x 10 x 3 inches); Contains souvenir and house programs, newspaper clippings, and photographs of Lillian Covillo's activities in the Denver ballet community prior to the founding of Colorado Ballet. This includes: Covillo-Parker School of Dance, Lillian Covillo Balllet Company, Covillo-Parker Theatre Ballet Company and related companies and performances. A scrapbook with snapshots of a Colorado Concert Ballet performance of ''Romeo and Juliet,'' choreographed by Freidann Parker, and the classes and studios at the East Colfax and Fairax studio is also included. (Box D022.0003)